Edward G. Ramberg Papers 1916-1994 Mss.Ms.Coll.88
American Philosophical Society
Edward G. Ramberg Papers
1916-1994
Mss.Ms.Coll.88
American Philosophical Society
11.5 Linear feet
A physicist and social activist, Edward G. Ramberg contributed to the early development of electron microscopy and color television, and devoted much of his life to pacifist and Quaker causes. Born in Italy to an American mother and German father, Ramberg experienced the losses of war firsthand during the First World War when his father was killed while serving with the German army. After moving to the United States with his mother, Ramberg attended Reed College and Cornell University before returning to Germany for postdoctoral study under Arnold Sommerfeld. Employed at RCA for most of his career (1935-1972), Ramberg refused any involvement in military or war-related research, and as a conscientious objector during the Second World War, was assigned to duty in Civilian Public Service camps. He continued to work in fostering social harmony until late in life. With his wife, Sarah Sargent, a Swarthmore graduate whom he met through the American Friends Service Committee, Ramberg helped to establish Bryn Gweled, a cooperative community in which people of various religious, social, and racial backgrounds lived and worked together. The bulk of the Ramberg papers consists of files pertaining to his work with Amnesty International, the American Friends Service Committee, and peace groups in the Philadelphia and Bucks County region. Of particular note is a bundle of correspondence with Sommerfeld.
Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907-
Related Archival Materials note
The Printed Materials Department at the APS has the following titles by Ramberg:
Sommerfeld, A., Electrodynamics: Lectures on theoretical physics, vol. 3. trans. by Edward G. Ramberg. (NY: Academic Press, 1952). Call no.: 537.6 so5e.
Zworykin, V.K., George Ashmun Morton, Edward G. Ramberg, James Hillier, and A. W. Vance, Electron Optics and the Electron Microscope (N.Y.: Wiley, 1945). Call no.: 578.1z9e
Other collections related to the Ramberg Papers include the Victor Paschkis Papers located at Swarthmore College and the Theodor Benfey Papers at Haverford College. Paschkis and Benfey were involved with the Society for Social Responsibility in Science.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The collection was donated to the APS by the Ramberg family in 1996.
Scope and Contents note
The Ramberg Papers contain 11.5 linear feet of correspondence, publications, and other materials that document the life of the physicist and peace activist, Edward G. Ramberg. Although the collection includes some correspondence and diaries from Ramberg's student days working under Arnold Sommerfeld in Munich, and some manuscript and printed materials relating to his research on electron microscopy and television at RCA in the 1930s-1940s, the heart of the collection is Ramberg's decades long concern with peace and social justice. In addition to some interesting materials relating to the Society of Friends, Ramberg kept files documenting his activities in the Society for Social Responsibility in Science (1948-1972) and in the Bucks County (Pa.) branch of Amnesty International.
Series I. Correspondence 1920-1994 1.0 linear feet
Series II. Personal 1916-1991 1.0 linear feet
Series III. RCA 1927-1973 3.5 linear feet
Series IV. SSRS (Society for Social Responsibility in Science) 1947-1974 0.5 linear feet
Series V. Peace concerns 1961-1994 1.5 linear feet
Series VI. Amnesty International 1975-1993 4.0 linear feet
Biographical/Historical note
A physicist and social activist, Edward Granville Ramberg was born in Florence, Italy, on June 14, 1907, to an American mother and German. Lucy (Dodd), an artist, and Walter, a philologist, surrounded their children Walter, Edward, and Lucy with art and culture, raising them in a rare cosmopolitan atmosphere in which they spoke French, German, Italian, and English. But Edward's life changed abruptly at seven, when his father was killed while serving with the German army.
After moving to Munich for the duration of the war, the Rambergs returned to Lucy's family home in Portland, Oregon, in 1920, graduating from Lincoln High two years later. An excellent student with a marked ability in quantitative sciences, Ramberg's collegiate career was neverthless marked by several interruptions. Although he enrolled at Reed College in 1922, he transferred to Cornell two years later, taking a hiatus from 1925-1927 to work in optical computation at Bausch and Lomb Optical Company. He decided to remain at Cornell after receiving his bachelor's degree in 1928 to work with F. K. Richtmyer, with whom he continued to collaborate throughout the 1930s.
In 1930, Ramberg went to Germany to sharpen his skills, receiving a doctorate under Arnold Sommerfeld at the University of Munich for "Doppelsprünge im Röntgenspektrum: Die Deutung Der Satelliten K α 3, 4" (1932). Although he returned to Cornell in 1932, continuing work on the theory of x-ray satellites and line widths, Ramberg soon moved to industry, joining RCA laboratories in Camden, New Jersey in 1935. As a junior engineer, he took part in both experimental and theoretical work on secondary emission, pickup tubes, and field emission, and later played a significant role in the development of the theory of thermoelectric refrigeration and image tube aberrations and in demonstrating the mathematical operability of a multistage electrostatic electron multiplier. Perhaps most famously, Ramberg, an expert in electron optics, took part in two particularly prominent projects: the development of color television in the late 1930s, and the construction of one of the first electron microscopes in the mid-1940s. He remained at RCA until 1972, when he retired with twenty-five patents to his credit.
Outside of RCA, Ramberg was a visiting professor in physics at the University of Munich in 1949 and was a Fulbright lecturer at the Technischehochschule in Darmstadt, Germany in 1960-1961. In 1964, he was awarded the David Sarnoff Outstanding Team Award in Science from RCA, and the David Sarnoff Award (co-sponsored by RCA and the IEEE) in 1972 for his work on electron optics, electron physics, and television. In addition to awards connected to RCA, Ramberg was made a Fellow of the American Physical Society in 1957, and received the Karl Ferdinand Braun Prize from the Society for Information Display in 1989. Ramberg was a member of the Electron Microscope Society of America, the American Association of Physics Teachers, the Society of Sigma XI, and the American Association for the Advancement of Science, and was made a Fellow of the Institute of Radio Engineers and the American Physical Society. He and Richtmyer received a research grant from the American Philosophical Society in 1935.
Although not a highly prolific author, Ramberg published five books during his career, four in collaboration with colleagues at RCA. He teamed with Viktor Zworykin. George Morton, and two other colleagues on an important early work in electron microscopy, Electron Optics and the Electron Microscope (N.Y., 1945), and he and Zworykin paired up again on Photoelectricity and its Application (1949) and Television in Science and Industry (1958). His final book was, written with A. M. Morell and H. B. Law, Color Television Picture Tubes, appeared in 1974. Ramberg also translated Arnold Sommerfeld's book Electrodynamics: Lectures on Theoretical Physics, vol. 3 (1952).
Building on the bitter early experience of losing his father in World War I, Ramberg became a committed pacifist and, after 1938, a devout member of the Society of Friends. With the outbreak of the Second World War, the federal government called upon Ramberg to continue work he had done on the metal structure of the electron microscope in order to make stronger shell casings, but he refused to participate. Claiming conscientious objector status, he refused all participation in the military and was assigned to Civilian Public Service. From 1943 to 1946, he was employed as an aide at a psychiatric facility in New Hampshire, in draining land in Maryland, and at Haskins Laboratory in New York City, where he worked on electronic aids for the blind. After his return to RCA in 1946, Ramberg devoted himself even more fervently to social reform and peace concerns. He was a founding member of the Society for Social Responsibility in Science (SSRS) in 1948, holding several positions with the organization through the years, including serving as president from 1958-1960. Still conscientiously abstaining from work on any project that contributed to warfare, he and his fellow members of the SSRS actively supported fellow conscientious scientists.
Ramberg married Sarah Sargent Ramberg on December 26, 1936. A graduate of Swarthmore College, Sarah had been working with the American Friends Service Committee when the couple met and broadly shared her husband's utopian values. She was deeply involved in the SSRS and was the editor of its Newsletter, and both she and her husband remained active in their Friends Meeting and in organizations such as Amnesty International. The Rambergs were one of thirteen families that founded Bryn Gweled in Upper Southampton Township, Bucks County, Pa., in 1941, a community designed to have equal positions for all of its members, regardless of race or gender. In a 1983 article in the Philadelphia Inquirer, Ramberg, still living at Bryn Gweled, was quoted as saying that they wanted "to have a place where families could bring their children and could live together in a group, a varied group, where they would learn there was more than one type of person in the world, more than one religion, more than one ethnic group and more than one economic group." He added, "I think that it has worked out... I think the basic idea of a cooperative has worked pretty well."
An untiring activist, Ramberg and his wife worked as draft counselors from 1968 to 1972 and traveled regularly to Washington, D.C., to protest the Vietnam War. For two years they took care of a foster daughter from Vietnam who was receiving medical treatments for phosphorous burns. During the 1970s, Ramberg worked at the Philadelphia Airport teaching minorities how to be qualified for positions as maintenance workers, and was deeply involved with the Friends Peace Committee of the Philadelphia Yearly Meeting, the Peace and Service Committee and the Committee on the United Nations of the Bucks Quarterly Meeting, and other Quaker organizations. He was one of the founding members of the Bucks County Group of Amnesty International in 1975. Politically, he was a Socialist from his days in college until 1972, when he and his wife became disenchanted with the party.
Sarah Ramberg died in May 1975 after a two year struggle with cancer. Edward Ramberg died on January 9, 1995.
Amnesty International. Bucks County (Pa.) Group; Amnesty International; Bopp, Friedrich Arnold, 1909–1987; Morton, George Ashmun, 1903-; Ramberg, Sarah Sargent; Ramberg, Walter, d. 1914; RCA Corporation; Richtmyer, F. K., (Floyd Karker), 1881-1939; Scherzer, Otto; Society for Social Responsibility in Science (ACT).; Sommerfeld, Arnold, 1868-1951; Vance, A. W.; Zworykin, V. K., (Vladimir Kosma), 1889-1982; Electron microscopy; Electron optics; Holography; Optics; Peace; Photographs; Physics; Quakers--Pennsylvania; Society of Friends; Television; Thermoelectricity; Vietnamese Conflict, 1961-1975
- Series I. Correspondence, 1916-1958; 1.0 Linear feet
  Scope and Contents note
  Ramberg's correspondence contains both outgoing and incoming letters with colleagues, friends, and family members. The most important letters may be those with Arnold Sommerfeld and his wife, written from the 1930s into the 1950s, but there are others from colleagues such as F. K. Richtmyer and V. K. Zworykin. The letters to family and friends are engaging, providing great insight into Ramberg's social views and reactions to current events. The most voluminous writers are his sister in law Maud Sargent, his brother Walter, and Walter's children Walter Dodd, Jenny, and Lucy, "Mirjam and Bele," and his friends the Scherzers. Otto Scherzer wrote in 1933 that the horror stories about Hilter were all propaganda. The slight majority of letters are written in German.
  Correspondence associated with Ramberg's research at RCA is located in Series III. A substantial quantity of correspondence with Ramberg's publisher, John Wiley and Sons, documents editorial changes and financial agreements for Ramberg's books. There is also some material relating to his travels in Europe as a Fulbright lecturer in Germany in 1960, including letters to and from colleagues in America and Europe.
  - Abeles, Benjamin, 1979; 2 items (Box 1)
  - Academic Work in Germany, 1949; 5 items (Box 1)
  - Aldred, Carol Ann, 1971, 1973; 3 items (Box 1)
  - Alphonse, Gerald A., 1973; 1 item (Box 1)
  - American Association of Physics Teachers, 1972; 2 items (Box 1)
  - American Institute of Physics, 1951; 1 item (Box 1)
  - American Physical Society, 1957; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Barnes, J.S., 1965; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Barrow, Bruce B., 1973; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Bass, Leon, 1970; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Bela, Ramon, 1961; 2 items (Box 1)
  - Bethe Hans, 1967; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Books for Asian Students, 1972; 5 items (Box 1)
  - Bopp, Fritz [Friedrich Arnold], 1950-1967; 7 items (Box 1)
    German
  - Bruche, E., 1947-1967; 11 items (Box 1)
  - Bucks County (Pa.). Draft Counseling Service, 1971, 1972; 4 items (Box 1)
  - Burgess, Alex M., 1945; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Burnay. G.(?), 1961; 4 items (Box 1)
  - Burns, John L., 1961; 1item (Box 1)
  - Byczkowski, Marie, 1972; 6 items (Box 1)
  - Bye, Mary, 1973, 1979; 3 items (Box 1)
  - Cappecchi, Mario, 1967-1989; 8 items (Box 1)
  - Chapman, R. Dabney, 1961; 6 items (Box 1)
  - Clark, Robert, 1969; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Cleef, Georgette, 1961; 4 item (Box 1)
  - Cohen, Peter G., 1968; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Cohen, R.W., 1972; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Coughenour, John F., Jr., n.d.; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Couthomel, Don, 1980; 1 item (Box 1)
  - DeBono, Roselle, 1952; 3 items (Box 1)
  - Deflandre, Mrs. Andre, 1961; 6 items (Box 1)
  - Dosse, J.(?), 1961; 4 items (Box 1)
  - Dow Corning Corporation, 1949; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Electron Optics and the Electron Microscope, 1946; 3 items (Box 1)
    John Wiley and Sons, publisher
  - Engler, Peter E., 1972, 1973; 4 items (Box 1)
  - Engstrom, E.W., 1954; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Engstrom, Ralph, W., 1978; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Eschbach, Franz, 1960, 1961; 2 items (Box 1)
  - Espinoza, J. Manuel, 1960; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Federation of American Scientists, 1994; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Fernandez-Moran, H. (?), 1972, 1973; 3 items (Box 1)
  - Fink, Donald G., 1971, 1973; 2 items (Box 1)
    Re. David Sarnoff Award
  - Flory, Leslie E., 1961; 3 items (Box 1)
  - Freson, M.(?), 1961; 2 items (Box 1)
  - Gabor, Dennis, 1971; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Gaegar, Erik, n.d.; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Geheimrat, (?), 1933-1951; 21 items (Box 1)
  - Gernert, Paul G., 1965; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Goldsmith, Alfred N., 1953, 1960; 2 items (Box 1)
  - Gorlich, P.(?), 1961; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Gory, Adrian E., 1945; 2 items (Box 1)
  - Gunther, Norbert, 1950, 1953, 1957; 6 items (Box 1)
  - Guth, W (?), 1961; 2 items (Box 1)
  - Hadlock, W.O., 1972; 2 items (Box 1)
  - Hannan, William J., 1972; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Harrah, James O., 1972; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Hayward, Herbert L., 1971; 2 items (Box 1)
  - Heinlin, Lore, 1952; 2 items (Box 1)
  - Heinz, H. John, 1987; 2 items (Box 1)
  - Herold, E. W., 1972, 1973; 3 items (Box 1)
  - Hersfeld, Karl F., 1948; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Hess, H(?), 1961; 2 items (Box 1)
  - Hillier, James, 1960-1961, 1972; 5 items (Box 1)
  - Hillstatts, R (?), 1932; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Hinterman, Eugen, 1950; 4 items (Box 1)
  - Hirsch, F.R., 1943; 1 item (Box 1)
  - [Howard], Adolf, n.d.; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Hume, Edgar Erskine, 1949; 3 items (Box 1)
  - Iceland Trip, 1973; 2 items (Box 1)
  - Irlbeck, Dennis H., 1980; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Jackson, Larry A., 1976, 1977; 8 items (Box 1)
    Re. Munich Reunion
  - Jacobson, Sol A., 1988; 2 items (Box 1)
  - Jacoby, Kurt, 1952-1953; 8 items (Box 1)
  - Japan International Christian University, 1955; 1 item (Box 1)
  - [Jodlbauer, Kurt], n.d.; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Johnson, Walter J., 1955; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Kanaya, K(?), 1962; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Karah, August El B., 1972, 1973; 2 items (Box 1)
  - Kennard, E.H., 1932; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Kennedy, David P., 1972; 2 items (Box 1)
  - Kennedy, John F., 1961; 2 items (Box 1)
    Letters to JFK
  - Khanamirian, A.K., 1949; 3 items (Box 1)
  - Kinder, E(?), 1948, 1949; 2 items (Box 1)
  - Klasen, Wilhelm, 1969; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Kluge, Werner, 1961; 2 items (Box 1)
  - Klugman, Ted, 1986; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Knoll, Max, 1948, 1961; 8 items (Box 1)
    German and English
  - Kooser, Ernst O., 1950; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Korus, Gunter, 1951-1952; 13 items (Box 1)
  - Kotasek, Frank, Jr., 1973; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Kuhlman, (?), 1948; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Kunze, Helmut, 1961; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Lalitha, P.(?), 1972; 2 items (Box 1)
  - Law, Harold B., 1960-1976; 18 items (Box 1)
  - Lerew, Henry, 1950; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Leverenz, T.W., 1961; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Lindsay, R.B., 1946; 2 items (Box 1)
  - Maddock, J. Kenneth, 1946, 1947; 7 items (Box 2)
    John Wiley and Sons
  - Mann, Paul August, 1950, 1951; 4 items (Box 2)
  - Marcussen, John, 1961; 2 items (Box 2)
  - Marton, L [Bill?], 1947, 1973; 5 items (Box 2)
  - Marx, Helmut, 1949, 1950; 2 items (Box 2)
  - Maucher, A (?), 1947-1950; 3 items (Box 2)
  - McClelland, David, 1945; 2 items (Box 2)
  - Meade, Mary, 1971, 1972; 4 items (Box 2)
  - Medical Aid for Indochina, Inc., 1972; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Menzel, Erich, 1972; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Merat, Parviz, 1953; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Merck, Emanuel W., 1961; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Metz, (?), n.d.; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Miller, Franklin, 1953-1967; 9 items (Box 2)
  - Miller, Lidie, 1972; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Millikan, Robert, 1950; 2 items (Box 2)
  - Mirjam and Bele (?), 1959-1973; 13 items (Box 2)
  - Mishkin, William, 1963; 4 items (Box 2)
  - Moritz, E.(?), 1950; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Moroni, Giovanni, 1950, 1953; 2 items (Box 2)
    Italian
  - Mueller, Friedrich, 1920-1929; 40 items (Box 2)
  - Muller, (?), 1921-1934; 6 items (Box 2)
  - Muller, Elizabeth, 1952-1960; 18 items (Box 2)
  - Muller, Henning, 1965; 1 item (Box 2)
  - O'Brien, John A., 1960; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Ogden, R.M., 1925; 1 item (Box 2)
    Cornell University Dean
  - Oppelt, Ing W., 1960; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Optical Society of America, 1926; 1 item (Box 2)
    Membership offer
  - Patchkis, Victor and Lucy, 1972-1987; 5 items (Box 2)
  - Perlow, Gilbert J., 1972; 2 items (Box 2)
  - Peters, Theodore J., 1968, 1970; 2 items (Box 2)
  - Peterson, Charles, 1987; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Piore, E.R., 1971; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Purdie, Arnold, 1973; 2 items (Box 2)
  - Ramberg, Edward G., 1972-1973; 6 items (Box 2)
  - Ramberg, Sarah Sargent, 1949-1961; 7 items (Box 2)
  - Ramberg, Walter, 1952-1979; 13 items (Box 2)
  - Ramberg, Walter Dodd, Jenny, and Lucy, 1967, 1968; 4 items (Box 2)
  - Rheinfelder, (?), 1949; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Rhoads, Ann, 1967; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Richtmeyer, F.K., 1928-1937; 7 items (Box 2)
  - Ringreisen, Josef, n.d.; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Romberg, Werner, 1949, 1961; 15 items (Box 2)
  - Rose, Albert, 1975; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Saenger, Werner, 1949; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Salber, Mena, 1933, 1935; 3 items (Box 2)
  - Sall, Chester W., 1972; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Sargent, Maud, 1952-1988; 3 items (Box 2)
  - Schaeffer, T.W., 1947; 4 items (Box 2)
  - Schantz, Faith, 1970; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Scherzer, Elizabeth, 1946, 1947; 3 items (Box 2)
  - Scherzer, Hanne, 1950; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Scherzer, Otto, 1933-1965; 58 items (Box 2)
  - Scherzer, Ursula, 1950; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Schimpf, Georg Wolfgang, 1960; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Schnabel, Herbert, 1968; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Schroter, Manfred, 1947-1949; 5 items (Box 2)
    German,
  - Schwarz, Gunther, 1960; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Sears, Roebuck, and Company, 1952; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Seiler, H.(?), 1971; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Selmayr, Karl, 1934-1949; 7 items (Box 2)
  - Shatzkin, Eleanor, 1972; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Simmons, L.N., 1927; 1 item (Box 2)
    Appointment for assistant in physics department at Cornell
  - Smith, Lloyd P., 1948, 1950; 3 items (Box 2)
  - Socialist Party, USA, 1970, 1972; 2 items (Box 2)
  - Society of Brothers, Inc., 1968; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Sommer, Al, 1961; 2 items (Box 2)
  - Sommerfeld, Arnold, 1933-1950; 3 items (Box 2)
  - Sommerfeld, Ernst, 1951; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Sommerfeld, Johanna, 1951, 1953; 5 items (Box 2)
    Bibliographical material on A.S. German
  - Souci, S.W., 1950; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Spicer, William F., 1961; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Stoger, Peter A., 1947; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Stumacher, Eric, 1966; 2 items (Box 2)
  - Sullivan, Warren, 1951; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Szymanski, Lucy Ramberg, 1969; 3 items (Box 2)
  - Triest, Rudolf M., 1944; 9 items (Box 2)
  - Uncle Caspar and Aunt Resel(?), 1933-1936; 14 items (Box 2)
  - United World Federalists, 1966 (Box 2)
  - Villesmer, G. (?), 1920; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Volkmann, H.(?), 1961; 5 items (Box 2)
  - Webster, W. (?), 1973; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Westover, J. Huston, 1957; 2 items (Box 2)
  - Wilson, E.W., 1946; 2 items (Box 2)
  - Wolf, Franz, 1961; 4 items (Box 2)
  - Zworykin, V.K., 1935-1973; 9 items (Box 2)
  - Unknown, 26 items (Box 2)
  - Unknown-Family, 32 items (Box 2)
- Series II. Personal, 1916-1991; 1.0 Linear feet
  The bulk of Series II consists of notes, essays, and documents relating to Ramberg's education, with the most important item being a set of notes he kept in Sommerfeld's class in Munich in 1930. There is little of a truly personal nature, with the exception of a few letters to his nephew Mario Cappecchi, a scientist, and a small amount of bibliographic material on Cappecchi.
  One item of particular interest is a photo album from the period that Ramberg was performing alternative service as a conscientious objector during the Second World War as a staff member at a New Hampshire psychiatric facility. This album includes pictures of workers and their wives with a list of their names and addresses, and is accompanied by some correspondence about changing his status and work. The remainder of the series consists of student identification cards, passports, school papers from Ramberg and his wife, academic material from his time as a graduate student in Germany, and a copy of his dissertation.
  - 1960, Cappecchi, Mario (Box 3)
    George School Commencement
  - Cornell University, 1930 (Box 3)
  - Cornell University-Academic Reports, 1930 (Box 3)
  - Cornell University --School Report, 1930 (Box 3)
  - Certificate of Appreciation, 1984; Democratic Party (Box 3)
  - Certificate of Recognition, 1984; Democratic Party (Box 3)
  - Fulbright, 1960-1961 (Box 3)
  - Photograph Book, 1944? (Box 3)
    New Hampshire Psychiatric Facility
  - Biographical Information, Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 3)
  - Class Notes, 1930-1931; 3 items; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 3)
  - Class Notes, 1931; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 3)
  - Class Notes -- A. Sommerfeld, 1930; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 3)
  - Clippings, n.d.; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 3)
  - Diaries, 1925; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 4)
  - Diaries, 1927, 1930, 1934; 6 items; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 4)
  - Doppelsprunge im Rüntgenspektrum: Die Deutung Der Satelliten Koc 3, 4 (Dissertation, University of Munich), 1932; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 4)
  - Driver's License, 1991; Ramberg, E. G., (Edward Granville), 1907- (Box 4)